Register of the Freda Utley Papers, 1886-1978
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches And Writings, Dated, 1930-1974
  - "Brief Interlude," Los Angeles Times, Mar. 28, 1957 (letter to the editor) (Folder 9)
  - "Visitor to Formosa Scores U.S. Policy on the Island," New York Herald-Tribune, June 15, 1957 (letter to the editor) (Folder 10)
  - Speech, Nov. 26, 1957 (Folder 11)
  - Letter to the editor, Middle East Journal, 1958 (Folder 12)
  - Radio interview, July 1958 (Tex and Jinx Jury program) (Folder 13)
  - Radio interview, July 15, 1958 (Life and the World program) (Folder 14)
  - Statement, Special Memorandum from Universal Research and Consultants, Inc., Oct. 17, 1958 (Folder 15)
  - "Taiwan Cause Supported: Nationalists Held Only Hope of Oppressed Mainland Chinese," New York Times, Nov. 1, 1958 (letter to the editor) (Folder 16)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Aug. 30, 1960 (date written) (Box 28., Folder 1)
  - "The Middle East and the Elections," Washington Post, Sept. 11, 1960 (letter to the editor) (Folder 2)
  - Letter to the editor, National Review, 1961 (Folder 3)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, Feb. 1, 1961 (date written) (Folder 4)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, Apr. 15, 1961 (Folder 5)
  - "Divide and Conquer," Oct. 20, 1961 (letter to the editor of the New York Times. date written) (Folder 6)
  - Untitled, July 10, 1964 (Folder 7)
  - Letter to the editor, Human Events, Nov. 23, 1964 (date written) (Folder 8)
  - "Israel on Trial," Triumph, Aug. 1967 (Folder 9)
  - Speech, Mar. 18, 1968 (Italian-German Friendship Association, Rome) (Folder 10)
  - "Strange Anniversary of the June War: Report from the West Bank," Triumph, June 1968 (Folder 11)
  - "Who Will Win the 'June War?': Report from the Holy Land," Triumph, June 1968 (Folder 12)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, June 10, 1968 (date written) (Folder 13)
  - "Upside Down Victory in the Holy Land," Arab World, Jan.-Feb. 1969 (Folder 14)
  - Odyssey of a Liberal, 1970
    - Drafts (Folder 15-17)
    - Galleys (Folder 18)
    - Promotional material (Box 29., Folder 1)
    - Reviews (Folder 2)
  - "Fulbright and the Mideast," Washington Post, Oct. 19, 1970 (letter to the editor) (Folder 3)
  - "God Save Israel (and Us) from Her Friends," Religion and Society, Feb. 1971 (Folder 4)
  - "Zionist Propaganda: An Evaluation of Its Effect upon the World," Daily Star (Beirut, Lebanon), May 9-10, 1971 (two-part article) (Folder 5)
  - "The Pro-Red China Lobby Rides Again: How China Was Lost," Human Events, Sept. 4, 1971 (Folder 6)
  - "Will Chou En-lai Outmaneuver Nixon?" Human Events, Oct. 9, 1971 (Folder 7)
  - "As the Bell Tolls for China," 1972 (Folder 8)
  - "John Carter Vincent," Washington Post, Jan. 1, 1973 (letter to the editor) (Folder 9)
  - "Forcing the Arabs into Devil's Arms," Washington Star-News, Oct. 21, 1973 (Folder 10)
  - "Who Can Be the Real Mideast Winner? The Kissinger Cease-Fire," Human Events, Nov. 24, 1973 (Folder 11)
  - "No Hope Except in God," Washington Star-News, Jan. 27, 1974 (review of Malcolm Muggeridge, Chronicles of Wasted Time: Chronicle 1: The Green Stick) (Folder 12)
  - "Repatriation Measured in Lives," Washington Star-News, Mar. 10, 1974 (review of Julius Epstein, Operation Keelhaul) (Folder 13)
  - "Oppression by a 'General Idea' Can Affect Us All," Human Events, May 11, 1974 (review of Malcolm Muggeridge, Chronicles of Wasted Time: Chronicle 1: The Green Stick) (Folder 14)
- Speeches And Writings, Undated
  - "Agrarian Crisis in Russia?" (Box 29., Folder 15)
  - "America House Libraries in Germany" (Folder 16)
  - "American Business between Two Fires" (Folder 17)
  - "Auction in the Far East" (Folder 18)
  - "Australia and Japan" (Folder 19)
  - "Bases of British Policy" (Folder 20)
  - "The Book of the Month Club Too!" (Folder 21)
  - "British Foreign Policy" (Folder 22)
  - "The Budget and Dismantlement" (Folder 23)
  - "The Camouflaged Communist Press" (Folder 24)
  - "Can Russia Win Germany? Ominous Reactions to the 'Contractual Agreement'" (Folder 25)
  - "Can Russia Win Our War?" (Folder 26)
  - "Can the New World Save the Old?" (Folder 27)
  - "Can We Be Sure of the Philippines?" (Folder 28)
  - "Can We Count upon Russia as an Ally?" (Folder 29)
  - "Cardboard Colossus" (Folder 30)
  - "Castlereagh's Strategy against Napoleon" (Folder 31)
  - "Chiang Kai-shek and the Communists" (Folder 32)
  - "China Focus of Conflict" (Folder 33)
  - "China's Camouflaged Communists" (Folder 34)
  - "China's Industrialization," Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury (Folder 35)
  - "China's Tragic Dilemma" (Folder 36)
  - "China's War Effort" (Folder 37)
  - "Chinese Communism" (Folder 38)
  - "Chinese Representation in the United Nations: An Analysis" (Folder 39)
  - "The Chinese Situation" (Folder 40)
  - "Coffee without Caffeine" (Folder 41)
  - "The Colonisation of Eastern Europe" (Folder 42)
  - "Communism in Asia" (Folder 43)
  - "Communism in the Middle East" (Folder 44)
  - "Communist Influence in America" (Folder 45)
  - "The Communist Menace in America" (Folder 46)
  - "Communist Myths" (Folder 47)
  - "Congress and the Preservation of Democracy" (Box 30., Folder 1)
  - "Contrasts on Formosa" (Folder 2)
  - "Coue Diplomacy" (Folder 3)
  - "The Crime of the 'China Experts' and the Drama of China Today" (Folder 4)
  - "Danger at Geneva" (Folder 5)
  - "The Dangerous Mr. Davis" (Folder 6)
  - "The Danubian Lands and the Balkans" (Folder 7)
  - "De Gaulle and Pandora's Box" (Folder 8)
  - "Did Communists Influence Our Far Eastern Policies?" (Folder 9)
  - "Dismantlement at Salzgitter: Hermann Goering Works" (Folder 10)
  - "Dry Well," National Review (review of Michael Bialoguski, The Case of Colonel Petrov) (Folder 11)
  - "The Economic and Political Structure of Fascist Germany" (Folder 12)
  - "Emergency Appeal to All Freedom-Loving People: Aid Refugees from Communism in China" (paid political advertisement; co-signer with other members of the Emergency Committee for Chinese Refugees) (Folder 13)
  - "The Enslaved Women of Japan" (Folder 14)
  - "Exit Economic Man: Enter Ethical Man?" Common Sense (review of Peter Drucker, The Future of Industrial Man: A Conservative Approach) (Folder 15)
  - "False Dawn in Chungking" (Folder 16)
  - "The Far East in World Affairs" (Folder 17)
  - "The Far East in World Politics" (Folder 18)
  - "The Far Eastern Crisis" (Folder 19)
  - "The Far Eastern Situation" (Folder 20)
  - "Feng Yu-hsiang" (Folder 21)
  - "Foreign Trade and Exchange Control" (Folder 22)
  - "Four Hundred Million Lost Allies" (Folder 23)
  - "The French Sickness" (Folder 24)
  - "From Mongolia to Madrid" (Folder 25)
  - "Full Circle" (Folder 26)
  - "German Realities" (Folder 27)
  - "Germany Abandons Japan for Russia" (Folder 28)
  - "Germany and Russia" (Folder 29)
  - "Good News from China" (Folder 30)
  - "How Communist Myths Are Spread in America" (Folder 31)
  - "How Dumb Can You Get?" (Folder 32)
  - "How Many Switzerlands?" (Folder 33)
  - "How We Blackmail the Germans" (Folder 34)
  - "I March with the Red Cross in China," Reynolds News (Folder 35)
  - "Ice Age or Iron Age" (review of Max Lerner, Ideas for the Ice Age, and William Henry Chamberlin, The World's Iron Age) (Folder 36)
  - "Illusions about Soviet Russia" (Folder 37)
  - "Imperialism" (Folder 38)
  - "The Italian-German Agreement" (Folder 39)
  - "Italy" (Folder 40)
  - "Japan and Russia" (Folder 41)
  - "Japan over China" (Folder 42)
  - "Japan Prepares to Don Sheep's Clothing" (Folder 43)
  - "The Japanese Budget" (Folder 44)
  - "Japan's Hopes of British Friendship" (Folder 45)
  - "Last Chance for Israel" (Folder 46)
  - "Laying Lenin's Ghost" (Folder 47)
  - Letter to the editor, National Review (Folder 48)
  - Letter to the editor, New Statesman and Nation (Folder 49)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Herald-Tribune (Folder 50)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times (Folder 51)
  - Letter to the editor, Times (London) (Folder 52)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Evening Star (Folder 53)
  - Letters to the editor, unknown publications (Folder 54)
  - Letters to the editor, Washington Post (Folder 55)
  - "'Like a God in France'" (Folder 56)
  - "'Mad Hatter's Party'" (letter to the editor) (Box 31., Folder 1)
  - "The Malmedy Case" (Folder 2)
  - "Manchuria" (Folder 3)
  - "The Miracle Railway" (Folder 4)
  - "'Moderates' and 'Extremists' in Japan'" (Folder 5)
  - "Moscow's Failure in the Middle East" (Folder 6)
  - "The Neutrals' War" (Folder 7)
  - "A New Bid from Peking to Cairo?" (Folder 8)
  - "The New Imperialism: National Socialism: Can We Escape It?" (Folder 9)
  - "The New Type of Fellow Traveller" (Folder 10)
  - "No Easy Way Out," American Mercury (Folder 11)
  - "One Step Backward, Two Steps Forward," National Review (Folder 12)
  - "An Open Letter to President Johnson by Middle East Specialists" (paid political advertisement; co-signer with others) (Folder 13)
  - "The Opening of the Gates" (Folder 14)
  - "Our German 'War Criminals'" (Folder 15)
  - "Our Liberal Bourbons" (Folder 16)
  - "Paris Is Not Europe" (Folder 17)
  - "Political Developments in Germany" (Folder 18)
  - "The Political World Is Also Round" (Folder 19)
  - "Post-Mortem on Capitalism" (Folder 20)
  - "The Quaker Report: A Dissent" (Folder 21)
  - "Raw Materials, Colonies, Markets, and 'Overpopulation'" (Folder 22)
  - "Recent Events in Europe and the Far Eastern War" (Folder 23)
  - "Red Star over Independence Square: The Strange Case of Edgar Snow and the Saturday Evening Post," Plain Talk (Folder 24)
  - "The Reluctant American Dragon" (Folder 25)
  - Review of Pearl Buck, Imperial Woman (Folder 26)
  - Review of James Burnham, The Coming Defeat of Communism (Folder 27)
  - Review of James Burnham, The Managerial Revolution (Folder 28)
  - Review of Alistair Cooke, A Generation on Trial (Folder 29)
  - Review of John Gunther, Behind the Curtain (Folder 30)
  - Review of Thor Heyerdahl, Kon-Tiki, and Erik Hesselberg, Kon-Tiki and I: A Sketch-book of the Famous Kon-Tiki Expedition (Folder 31)
  - Review of Douglas Hyde, I Believe (Folder 32)
  - Review of John F. Kennedy, Profiles in Courage (Folder 33)
  - Review of Owen Lattimore, The Situation in Asia (Folder 34)
  - Review of Herbert Luethy, France against Herself (Folder 35)
  - Review of Felix Morley, The Power in the People (Folder 36)
  - Review of Komakichi Nohara, The True Face of Japan, Edgar Lajtha, The March of Japan, Hessel Tiltman, The Far East Comes Nearer, Guenther Stein, Far East in Ferment, and E. N. Courton, Militarism and Foreign Policy in Japan (Folder 37)
  - Review of George Orwell, 1984 (Folder 38)
  - Review of Henry L. Roberts, Russia and America: Dangers and Prospects (Folder 39)
  - Review of A. L. Sadler, The Maker of Modern Japan: The Life of Tokugawa Ieyasu (Folder 40)
  - Review of Philip Spratt, Blowing up India (Folder 41)
  - Review of Edward R. Stettinius, Jr., Roosevelt and the Russians: The Yalta Conference (Folder 42)
  - Review of George R. Stewart, The Years of the City (Folder 43)
  - Review of John L. Strohm, Just Tell the Truth (Folder 44)
  - Review of G. A. Tokaev, Betrayal of an Idea (Folder 45)
  - Review of Harry S. Truman, Memoirs (Folder 46)
  - "Right and Left Illusions" (Folder 47)
  - "The Russian Dilemma" (Folder 48)
  - "Russian Neutrality" (Folder 49)
  - "Russo-Chinese Rapprochement" (Folder 50)
  - "The Saar: Test Case for Democracy and European Defense" (Folder 51)
  - "Shall It Profit Us to Betray China?" (Folder 52)
  - "Shall Not the Judge of All the Earth Do Right?" (Folder 53)
  - "Shanghai" (Folder 54)
  - "Signs and Significance of the Communist Turn to a 'Soft' Line" (Folder 55)
  - "The Sky Is Dark" (Folder 56)
  - "Socialism Must Be Democratic" (Folder 57)
  - "Some Contradictions in British Foreign Policy" (Folder 58)
  - "Stalin's Left Hand in America" (Folder 59)
  - Statement, U.S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee (Folder 60)
  - "A Statue to Patton" (Folder 61)
  - "The Strange Case of Japan" (Folder 62)
  - "Structure of the Nazi State" (Folder 63)
  - "Those Whom the Gods Wish to Destroy..." (Folder 64)
  - "Total War and the Nemesis of Imperialism" (Folder 65)
  - "Tragedy or Triumph on the Nile, or, Should We Back Nasser?" (Folder 66)
  - "Truth Will Out," Freeman (review of Walter Millis, ed., The Forrestal Diaries) (Folder 67)
  - "Turn the Flood of Lend Lease Over to China!" (Folder 68)
  - "Unending Quest" (Box 32., Folder 1)
  - Untitled (Folder 2)
  - "Versailles Treaty" (Folder 3)
  - "A Visit to Quemoy" (Folder 4)
  - "The War to Make the World Safe for Stalin" (Folder 5)
  - "What Is Behind the Attempt to Discredit Congress?" (Folder 6)
  - "What Is the Stalin Plan?" (Folder 7)
  - "What Is to Be Done in the Far East?" (Folder 8)
  - "What of the Chemical Revolution? Synthetics and the Future" (co-author with Alexander Baird) (Folder 9)
  - "What Power Has the Mikado?" (Folder 10)
  - "What's Wrong with the Right - and the Left Too, or, A Plague on Both Your Houses" (Folder 11)
  - "Where Liberty Is Not" (Folder 12)
  - "Where the Fate of the World Is Being Decided" (Folder 13)
  - "Whither Bound?" (Folder 14)
  - "Who Are the Chinese Liberals?" (Folder 15)
  - "Who Rules Japan?" (Folder 16)
  - "Why German Industrialists Need Public Relations in the United States" (Folder 17)
  - "Why I Like You" (Folder 18)
  - "Why Japan Cannot Face a Long War" (Folder 19)
  - "Why So Tender to Nehru? or, As the Pakistanis See Us" (Folder 20)
  - "Will America Fall for Nehru?" (Folder 21)
  - "Will Germany Turn East or West? Importance of the Paris Conference" (Folder 22)
  - "Will the Chinese Communists Break the United Front?" (Folder 23)
  - "The World Views the U.S." (column) (Folder 24)
  - "The Wrong Premise" (Folder 25)
  - "Yesterday China, Tomorrow the Middle East, or, Last Chance in the Middle East" (Folder 26)
  - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, FRAGMENTS OF, n.d. (Folder 27-28)
  - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, FRAGMENTS OF, n.d. (Box 33., Folder 1-4)
  - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, FRAGMENTS OF, n.d. (Box 34., Folder 1-4)
  - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, FRAGMENTS OF, n.d. (Box 35., Folder 1-4)
  - SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, FRAGMENTS OF, n.d. (Box 36., Folder 1-4)
- Notebooks, n.d.
  - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 37-40.)
  - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 41., Folder 1-3)
  - Calling cards n.d. (Folder 4)
- Subject File, 1936-1976
  - Africa (Box 42., Folder 1)
  - Algeria (Folder 2-3)
  - Asia (Folder 4-5)
  - Asia (Box 43., Folder 1)
  - China
    - General (Folder 2-3)
    - Bulletins (Box 44., Folder 1-3)
    - Printed matter (Box 45., Folder 1-5)
    - Printed matter (Box 46., Folder 1-5)
    - Printed matter (Box 47., Folder 1-2)
    - Speeches (by persons other than Freda Utley) (Folder 3)
  - Communism (communism in the United States or in international aspects only; material on communism in countries other than the United States filed under geographical headings) (Folder 4)
  - Communism (Box 48., Folder 1-3)
  - Dennis, Lawrence. see also CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL (Folder 4)
  - Eastman, Max (includes draft of "The Fate of the World Is at Stake in China" by Max Eastman and J. B. Powell) see also CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL (Folder 5)
  - Egypt
    - General (Box 49., Folder 1)
    - Bulletins (Folder 2-4)
    - Printed matter (Folder 5)
    - Printed matter (Box 50., Folder 1-5)
    - Printed matter (Box 51., Folder 1-4)
    - Speeches and interviews of Gamal Abdel Nasser (mimeographed) (Folder 5)
  - Europe
    - General (Box 52., Folder 1)
    - Printed matter (Folder 2-4)
  - France (Folder 5)
  - France (Box 53., Folder 1-2)
  - Germany
    - General (Folder 3-5)
      - General (Box 54., Folder 1)
      - Displaced persons (post-World War II) (Folder 2)
      - Reparations (post-World War II) (Folder 3-4)
      - War crime trials (post-World War II) (Box 55., Folder 1-4)
    - Press summaries (Box 56., Folder 1-2)
    - Printed matter (Folder 3-4)
    - Printed matter (Box 57., Folder 1-4)
    - Printed matter (Box 58., Folder 1-4)
    - Printed matter (Box 59., Folder 1-5)
  - Great Britain (Box 60., Folder 1-3)
  - Hong Kong (Folder 4)
  - India
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Printed matter (Box 61., Folder 1-5)
  - Iran (Box 62., Folder 1)
  - Iraq (Folder 2-3)
  - Israel
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Printed matter (Folder 5)
    - Printed matter (Box 63., Folder 1-5)
    - Printed matter (Box 64., Folder 1-2)
  - Italy (Folder 3)
  - Japan (Folder 4-5)
  - Japan (Box 65., Folder 1-2)
  - Jordan (Folder 3-4)
  - Korea (Folder 5)
  - Kuwait (Box 66., Folder 1)
  - Latin America (Folder 2)
  - Lattimore, Owen (includes draft of "Japan, Nanking and the Chinese Red Armies" by Owen Lattimore) see also CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL; and BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, under Clippings (Folder 3-4)
  - Lebanon (Folder 5-6)
  - Lebanon (Box 67., Folder 1)
  - Libya (Folder 2)
  - McCarthy, Joseph R. see also CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL (Folder 3-5)
  - Nasser, Gamal Abdel. see Egypt; CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL
  - Near East
    - General (Folder 6)
    - General (Box 68., Folder 1)
    - Printed matter (Folder 2-4)
    - Printed matter (Box 69., Folder 1-4)
    - Printed matter (Box 70., Folder 1-5)
  - Poland (Box 7l., Folder 1-2)
  - Powell, J. B. see Eastman, Max; CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL, under China Weekly Review
  - Russell, Bertrand. see also CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL (Folder 3)
  - Russia
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Printed matter (Folder 5-6)
    - Printed matter (Box 72., Folder 1-3)
  - Saudi Arabia (Folder 4-5)
  - Schieber, Haviv (Box 73., Folder 1)
  - Spain (Folder 2)
  - Starr, Park and Freeman Company. see also CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL (Folder 3-5)
  - Syria (Folder 6)
  - Taiwan (Box 74., Folder 1-4)
  - United States (see also Communism)
    - General (Box 75., Folder 1-2)
    - Printed matter (Folder 3-4)
    - Printed matter (Box 76., Folder 1-4)
    - Printed matter (Box 77., Folder 1-4)
    - Printed matter (Box 78., Folder 1-3)
  - Vietnam (Folder 4)
  - Vietnam (Box 79., Folder 1-2)
  - Wedemeyer, Albert C. (see also CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL)
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Wedemeyer Reports! (drafts of the book by Albert C. Wedemeyer) (Folder 4)
    - Wedemeyer Reports! (drafts) (Box 80., Folder 1-3)
  - Welles, Sumner (notes for interview) (Box 81., Folder 1)
  - Wittfogel, Karl A. (draft of Chapter 9 of Oriental Despotism by Karl A. Wittfogel) see also CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL (Folder 2)
  - World Anti-Communist League (Folder 3-4)
  - World politics
    - General (Folder 5-6)
    - Printed matter (Box 82., Folder 1-5)
    - Printed matter (Box 83., Folder 1-5)
  - World War, 1939-1945 (Box 84., Folder 1-4)
  - Yugoslavia (Folder 5)